<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | Drögemöller Lab</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are sad to say goodbye to Lexi, Emily and Prats after spending the summer in the lab!</title>
      <link>/post/23-08-30-summer_students/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-08-30-summer_students/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was a pleasure to listen to your final presentations!
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/chrim_lexi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;/img/chrim_prats.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Samah for being awarded the Human Genetics Endowment Fund Graduate Student Award!</title>
      <link>/post/23-07-30-samah-bmg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-07-30-samah-bmg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Samah for being awarded two Centre on Aging awards!</title>
      <link>/post/23-07-01-samah-aging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-07-01-samah-aging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Jack MacDonell Scholarship for Research in Aging and Betty Havens Centre on Aging Graduate Fellowship!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deanne attends the bioinformatics.ca RNAseq and scRNAseq workshops!</title>
      <link>/post/23-06-30-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-06-30-conferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on receiving a travel award to attend this course!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s been a busy month for everyone in the lab!</title>
      <link>/post/23-06-29-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-06-29-conferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great to see Samah winning the Big Data Challenge at the VADA Summer School and attending the CIHR-IA Summer Program in Aging, Deanne presenting at the Pharmacogenomics Global Research Network Meeting, Deanne and Avital presenting at the Manitoba Neuroscience Network Meeting, Deanne and Feryal presenting at the Canadian Society for Pharmacology and Therapeutics Meeting, and Feryal presenting at Prairie Cancer Research Consortium Conference!
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/June23.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congrats to Samah who did an awesome job representing us at the Otolaryngology Research Day</title>
      <link>/post/23-05-26-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-05-26-conferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/ENT_2023.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samah, Deanne, Feryal and Avital represent the Drögemöller Lab at the first BMG Research Day!</title>
      <link>/post/23-05-19-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-05-19-conferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are so proud of Samah and Feryal for winning the MSc and undergrad categories!
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/bmg_2023a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Alexandria Martin, Emily Allan and Pratyaksh Singhal, who will be joining the lab as summer students!</title>
      <link>/post/23-05-01-welcome_summer_students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-05-01-welcome_summer_students/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congrats to Alexandria for receiving an NSERC USRA and CHRIM Summer Studentship and Prats for receiving the Stem Cell Network and CHRIM Summer Studentships.
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/summerstudents_2023.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Deanne for being awarded a Research Manitoba MSc studentship and for being accepted into the Visual and Automated Disease Analytics Graduate Training Program!</title>
      <link>/post/23-04-01-deanne_vada_rady/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-04-01-deanne_vada_rady/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.umanitoba.ca/rady-grad-student-profile-deanne-nixie-miao-seeks-genetic-clues-to-hearing-loss-caused-by-cancer-drug/?fbclid=IwAR2KVAoupwsehmibWgyGKEulIX3rIEsN0ae8r4vwaTOmeNeE_44g2EubMbQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Rady grad student profile&lt;/a&gt; related to this award!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Drögemöller Lab is grateful to have received a CIHR CLSA Catalyst Grant</title>
      <link>/post/23-03-15-clsa_grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-03-15-clsa_grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with co-PI, Galen Wright, we will be using these funds to explore neglected regions of the genome and their link to age-related hearing loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Age related hearing impairment (ARHI) affects approximately half of individuals older than 75, making it one of the most common sensory impairments in the older Canadian population.  While clinical/demographic factors such as age, noise exposure and ototoxic drugs have been shown to increase the risk of experiencing hearing loss, genetics also plays a vital role in ARHI. Standard genome-wide association studies (GWAS) have uncovered genetic variants that are associated with ARHI. However, a large proportion of the observed heritability remains to be uncovered. This can largely be attributed to the following knowledge gaps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inaccurate ARHI phenotyping: Due to the extensive time and labour required to accurately assess hearing phenotypes using audiograms, large-scale GWAS have focused on using self-reported hearing phenotypes. Due to limitations in the accuracy of self-reported phenotypes, and the inability to classify individuals into different hearing loss phenotypes (e.g., metabolic and sensory phenotypes) using these data, there remain significant gaps in our understanding of ARHI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neglection of certain genomic regions: Previous GWAS of ARHI have focused on the association between common autosomal genetic variants, generally one base pair in length, and ARHI. However, as short tandem repeats (STRs) represent the largest source of variation in the genome and have been shown to play an important role in neurological and age-related phenotypes, the association between these variants and ARHI requires examination. Further, given the striking differences in ARHI between males and females, the lack of information regarding the association between genetic variants on the X-chromosome and ARHI requires addressing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aim to address these knowledge gaps through the following objectives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objective 1: Automate the classification of hearing impairment using audiogram configurations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objective 2: Assess the contribution of imputed STRs to ARHI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objective 3: Use these unique data to perform a large-scale XWAS and GWAS of ARHI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samah and Deanne represent the Drögemöller Lab at ICHG in Cape Town, South Africa!</title>
      <link>/post/23-02-19-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-02-19-conferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So proud of these two for presenting our work at the international congress of human genetics. Big congratulations to Samah who received presentation awards at the both the young researchers&amp;rsquo; forum and the main conference!
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/ICHG_Deanne.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/ICHG_Samah.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are sad to say goodbye to Niel after spending a three-month postdoctoral exchange in our lab!</title>
      <link>/post/23-02-15-niel_farewell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-02-15-niel_farewell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;but were happy to see that not even Winnipeg winters can keep a South African away from their braai!
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Niel_braai.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Drögemöller presents at the inaugural Canada Research Chairs symposium</title>
      <link>/post/23-02-02-crc_symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-02-02-crc_symposium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event featured presentations by twelve CRCs from across Faculties at Fort Gary and Bannatyne campuses
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/CRC_symposium.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A great start to 2023, with the publication of our transcriptome-wide association study of polycystic ovary syndrome</title>
      <link>/post/23-02-01-publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-02-01-publication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Sarah for leading this project!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/coloc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some key find from this work below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our TWAS uncovered an association between imputed &lt;em&gt;ARL14EP&lt;/em&gt; expression and PCOS in two independent cohorts. We validated these findings by examining measured &lt;em&gt;ARL14EP&lt;/em&gt; expression in a third PCOS cohort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colocalization analyses revealed tissue-specific eQTLs patterns - high evidence of colocalization was observed for the &lt;em&gt;ARL14EP&lt;/em&gt;-testis-PCOS triplet. As hyperandrogenism is a defining feature of PCOS, future studies should investigate how testosterone modulates the effects of &lt;em&gt;ALR14EP&lt;/em&gt; eQTLs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We showed that PCOS-associated &lt;em&gt;ARL14EP&lt;/em&gt; eQTLs occur in an &lt;em&gt;ARL14EP&lt;/em&gt; divergent transcript. Antisense lncRNAs can influence the expression of their coding gene counterparts. Future stdies should investigate the link between PCOS-associated variants, &lt;em&gt;ARL14EP-DT&lt;/em&gt; function and &lt;em&gt;ARL14EP&lt;/em&gt; expression.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ARL14EP&lt;/em&gt; has been shown to play an important role in chromatin remodelling. Annotation analyses revealed that &lt;em&gt;ARL14EP&lt;/em&gt; occurs within a region where extensive chromatin interactions are observed, including interactions with &lt;em&gt;FSHB&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/interaction.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While none of the gene prioritization analyses prioritized &lt;em&gt;FSHB&lt;/em&gt; as a likely causal gene, FSH levels are important in PCOS! Single cell multiomics analyses will provide improved insight into how &lt;em&gt;FHSB&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ARL14EP&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ARL14EP-DT&lt;/em&gt; interact in the relevant cells in the context of PCOS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more here: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rdcu.be/c4wCo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://rdcu.be/c4wCo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is always fun to celebrate with this amazing group of people!</title>
      <link>/post/22-12-04-lab_year_end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-12-04-lab_year_end/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While we are sad that this will be MacKenzie&amp;rsquo;s last celebration as a member of the Drögemöller lab, we wish her all the best in her new position at the National Microbiology Lab!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/year_end_2022.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congrats to Deanne for being awarded a Rady Faculty of Health Sciences Graduate Studentship!</title>
      <link>/post/22-12-01-congrats_deanne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-12-01-congrats_deanne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deanne will be using scRNAseq to examine cisplatin-induced changes in gene expression that occur in the inner ear&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to MacKenzie for successfully defending her MSc Thesis!</title>
      <link>/post/22-11-16-congrats_mackenzie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-11-16-congrats_mackenzie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You did an outstanding job and we are so proud of all the hard work you put into your MSc
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/mackenzie_msc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/hat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deanne and Feryal represent the Drögemöller Lab at the CancerCare Research Day!</title>
      <link>/post/22-10-25-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-10-25-conferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They did an awesome job presenting on how polygenic risk scores can be used to predict chemotherapy-related adverse drug reactions!
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/CC_Deanne.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/CC_Feryal.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Drögemöller attends the University of Alberta Medical Genetics Research Day!</title>
      <link>/post/22-10-19-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-10-19-conferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was great to give a keynote presentation and have dinner with some of the trainees!
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/UofA.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacKenzie and Sarah represent the Drögemöller Lab at CSPT in Montreal!</title>
      <link>/post/22-09-07-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-09-07-conferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great to see them presenting at their first in person conference!
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/CSPT.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It has been a busy start to Deanne&#39;s MSc!</title>
      <link>/post/22-09-01-welcome_deanne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-09-01-welcome_deanne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great to see Deanne attend the Jax hearing workshop and spend a week with Drs. Alain Dabdoub and Emilia Luca at Sunnybrook Research Institute. Congrats for receiving funding from the NIH to attend the Jax course!
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/jax_poster.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Avital, who will be joining the lab for her Genetics Honours project!</title>
      <link>/post/22-09-01-welcome_avital/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-09-01-welcome_avital/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Avital will be looking into the genetics of hidden hearing loss&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After two years of working in the lab, we are really sad to say goodbye to Sarah</title>
      <link>/post/22-07-30-sarah-farewell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-07-30-sarah-farewell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We wish you all the best for the future! It was great to celebrate together one more time!
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/activate.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Drögemöller Lab is grateful to have received an NSERC Discovery Grant!</title>
      <link>/post/22-06-27-grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-06-27-grants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These funds will be used to support work aimed at understanding the genomics of age-related hearing impairment through the use of automated phenotyping strategies and single cell RNA sequencing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More congratulations to MacKenzie Wilke for being awarded the Caroline A. Cope award for excellence in oncology research!</title>
      <link>/post/22-06-20-congrats_mackenzie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-06-20-congrats_mackenzie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are so proud of the contributions you are making to this field of research!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big congratulations to MacKenzie Wilke for being awarded the FGS Research Completion scholarship!</title>
      <link>/post/22-05-29-congrats_mackenzie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-05-29-congrats_mackenzie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been an absolute pleasure watching your research progress to this point!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Drögemöller Lab takes part in the Seven Oaks School Division STEM Hub</title>
      <link>/post/22-05-17-stem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-05-17-stem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This hub is aimed at providing high school students who are interested in STEM careers with the opportunity to meet with career professionals. The Team did an awesome job showing Hanna and Ridhi some wet and dry lab basics!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/stem.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/stem2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Drögemöller Lab finally attends our first in person meetings!</title>
      <link>/post/22-05-07-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-05-07-conferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congrats to Samah who did an awesome job representing us at the &lt;em&gt;University of Manitoba Otolaryngology Research Day&lt;/em&gt;, while Dr Drögemöller debated the value of polygenic scores for pharmacogenomics at the joint &lt;em&gt;Pharmacogenomics Global Research Network Meeting and Clinical Pharmacogenetics Implementation Consortium Meeting&lt;/em&gt; in Denver.
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/ENT.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Bilal Cheema for completing his Genetics Honours project!</title>
      <link>/post/22-05-02-congrats_bilal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-05-02-congrats_bilal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was great to have you join the lab and we wish you all the best with your future endeavours!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Feryal Ladha, who will be joining the lab as a summer student!</title>
      <link>/post/22-05-01-welcome_feryal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-05-01-welcome_feryal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congrats on receiving a CancerCare Manitoba Research Institute Summer Studentship!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lab goes bowling</title>
      <link>/post/22-04-19-bowling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-04-19-bowling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was great to get out and celebrate everyone&amp;rsquo;s hard work over the last couple of months!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/bowling.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More congratulations are in order for Samah for being awarded a Research Manitoba MSc studentship (declined) and for being accepted into the Visual and Automated Disease Analytics Graduate Training Program!</title>
      <link>/post/22-04-05-samah_vada/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-04-05-samah_vada/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Drögemöller and Wright labs hosted a Precision Medicine Workshop in South Africa as a part of their Carnegie African Diaspora Fellowships</title>
      <link>/post/22-02-01-carnegie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-02-01-carnegie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop was made possible through funding from Stellenbosch University and the CADPF. The workshop provided an overview of current genomic analyses and resources of relevance to pharmacogenomics and precision medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/carnegie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/carnegie2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congrats to Samah for being awarded a Rady Faculty of Health Sciences Graduate Studentship!</title>
      <link>/post/22-02-04-samah_rady/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-02-04-samah_rady/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Samah will be exploring the use of new phenotyping strategies to uncover genes and pathways underlying age-related hearing loss&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first article from the Drögemöller Lab is out!</title>
      <link>/post/22-01-01-publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-01-01-publication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great start to 2022, with the publication of our first article! Under the joint leadership of Danielle, MacKenzie and Sarah, we performed a systematic review and analysis of the current use of polygenic scores in pharmacogenomics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some key find from this work are highlighted below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development of PGx PGS is limited by a lack of large PGx cohorts. To overcome these challenges current studies are using PGS derived from non-drug related phenotypes. Large PGx consortiums are required to overcome these sample size limitations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A wide range of methods are currently being used to develop PGx PGS. Inconsistencies in reporting of methods complicates replication of findings. Future publications should adhere to PGS reporting standards: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03243-6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03243-6&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/PRS-RS.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lack of representation of authors from across the globe is contributing to the lack of diversity in participants that are included in PGx PGS research. We need to do better as a global community to prevent this research from increasing already existing health disparities
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/map.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more here: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ascpt.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cpt.2520&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://ascpt.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cpt.2520&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We have had a busy month of conferences!</title>
      <link>/post/21-10-22-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-10-22-meetings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congrats to MacKenzie Wilke and Sarah Lyle for representing Canada at the &lt;em&gt;Pharmacogenomics Global Research Network Meeting&lt;/em&gt; and both receiving top abstract awards! Also to MacKenzie for receiving a silver award in the &lt;em&gt;Child Health Research Days Conference&lt;/em&gt; (MSc category).
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/PGRN.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Bilal Cheema, who has joined the lab for a Honour&#39;s project, and Deanne Nixie Miao, who is working part-time as a technician in the lab!</title>
      <link>/post/21-09-01-welcome_bilal_deanne/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-09-01-welcome_bilal_deanne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to have you join the lab!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After more than a year of working together virtually, the vaccinated Drögemöller Lab finally had the opportunity to celebrate in person!</title>
      <link>/post/21-08-14-in-person-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-08-14-in-person-social/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/lablunch.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was great to have the Wright Lab join us!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Drögemöller Lab is extremely thankful for support from various funding agencies!</title>
      <link>/post/21-07-01-grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-07-01-grants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few months the Drögemöller Lab has received funding from &lt;strong&gt;CIHR&lt;/strong&gt; (Operating Grant: Early Career Investigators in Maternal, Reproductive, Child &amp;amp; Youth Health); &lt;strong&gt;Research Manitoba&lt;/strong&gt; (New Investigator Operating Grant) and the &lt;strong&gt;Health Sciences Centre Foundation&lt;/strong&gt; (General Operating Grant). We appreciate your support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These funds will be used to support work aimed at predicting and preventing hearing loss caused by the chemotherapeutic agent, cisplatin. These funds will allow us to develop polygenic risk scores to predict cisplatin-induced ototoxicity; use genomics-driven drug repurposing to identify novel otoprotectants to prevent and cisplatin-induced ototoxicity; and harness single cell RNA sequencing to identify cisplatin-induced changes in gene expression that occur in murine inner ear cells.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Samah Ahmed, who will be joining the lab as an MSc student!</title>
      <link>/post/21-06-01-welcome_samah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-06-01-welcome_samah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congrats on receiving the International Graduate Student Entrance Scholarship, Samah! Samah will be working on using single cell sequencing and GWAS to gain insight into the genomics of hearing loss traits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Urim Iyasere and Vaibhav, who will be joining the lab as summer students!</title>
      <link>/post/21-05-01-welcome_urim-vaibhav/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-05-01-welcome_urim-vaibhav/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congrats on receiving the CancerCare Manitoba Research Institute and Children’s Hospital Research Institute of Manitoba (CHRIM) Undergraduate Summer Studentships!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Sarah Lyle for completing her Genetics Honours project!</title>
      <link>/post/21-04-30-congrats_sarah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-04-30-congrats_sarah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In addition to Sarah completing her Honours project focusing on the genetics of polycystic ovary syndrome, we are also thrilled that Sarah will be staying on in the lab as a Co-op student!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To celebrate everyone&#39;s hard work over the last couple of months we took part in a Heist</title>
      <link>/post/21-04-09-escape-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-04-09-escape-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to some very clever people in the lab, we successfully completed this escape room game (despite &amp;ldquo;helpful&amp;rdquo; contributions from the PI)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/escape.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big congratulations to MacKenzie Sarvis for being awarded the CIHR-CGS-M and for being accepted into the Visual and Automated Disease Analytics Graduate Training Program!</title>
      <link>/post/21-04-01-congrats_mackenzie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-04-01-congrats_mackenzie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are really proud of all of MacKenzie&amp;rsquo;s hard work!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Danielle Johnson, who will be joining the lab as a Mitacs-Globalink UK-Canada PhD exchange student!</title>
      <link>/post/21-02-01-welcome_danielle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-02-01-welcome_danielle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Danielle will be joining us remotely from the UK to perform a systematic review of the use of polygenic risk scores in the field of pharmacogenomics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Drögemöller and Wright labs receive Carnegie African Diaspora Fellowships for their Graduate Training and Collaborative Research in Neurogenomics and Precision Medicine application</title>
      <link>/post/20-09-01-carnegie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/20-09-01-carnegie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This funding has been provided to support a collaboration between the University of Manitoba and Stellenbosch University in South Africa to develop (i) a genomics analysis pipeline for the improved diagnosis and treatment of neurological diseases in Manitoba and South Africa and (ii) workshops aimed at training graduate students in Neurogenomics &amp;amp; Precision Medicine at the University of Manitoba, Canada and Stellenbosch University, South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advances in genomic technologies and related analyses provide unprecedented opportunities for the field of precision medicine. Importantly, these advances have resulted in improvements in the diagnosis and treatment of neurological diseases. Unfortunately, African individuals have been under-represented in genomics research. Highlighting these disparities, it has been shown that although European descent individuals make up only 16% of the global population, they represent approximately 79% of participants that are included in genome-wide association studies. By developing international collaborations, as well as innovative graduate training strategies that merge the fields of neurogenomics and precision medicine, strategies can be developed to improve the diagnosis and treatment of neurological diseases in the context of Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacKenzie Sarvis is officially the first graduate student in the Drögemöller lab!</title>
      <link>/post/20-09-01-welcome_mackenzie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/20-09-01-welcome_mackenzie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MacKenzie will be working on developing a polygenetic risk score to predict chemotherapy-induced ototoxicity (hearing loss) and using drug repurposing analyses to identify otoprotectants to prevent this debilitating adverse drug reaction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Sarah Lyle, who will be joining the lab for her Genetics Honours project!</title>
      <link>/post/20-09-01-welcome_sarah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/20-09-01-welcome_sarah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sarah will be using transcriptome-wide association analyses to identify genes that contribute to polycystic ovary syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to MacKenzie Sarvis, the lab&#39;s first student!</title>
      <link>/post/20-06-01-first_summer_student/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/20-06-01-first_summer_student/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Excited to have MacKenzie Sarvis join the Drögemöller lab as a summer student&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
